http://www.finance.gov.au/government/commonwealth-contracting-suite-privacy-statement

Commonwealth Contracting Suite – Privacy Statement | Department of Finance
Commonwealth Contracting Suite – Privacy Statement
The Commonwealth Contracting Suite (CCS) website is maintained by the Department of Finance (Finance). Finance may collect, hold, use and disclose personal information to carry out our functions or activities in compliance with the Privacy Act 1988 (Privacy Act) and the Australian Privacy Principles (APPs).
Finance has developed a Privacy Policy which outlines how the department handles and protects personal information, including how to make a complaint and who to contact if you have a query, feedback or other request.
This statement applies to the personal information collected, used and disclosed by Finance as part of administering the CCS. It sets out each type of personal information that we collect and the primary purpose for which we collect that information. You should note that Finance may also use and disclose your personal information for a secondary purpose where an exception in the APPs applies.
The term ’personal information’ in this statement has the meaning given in the Privacy Act.
Contacting us
If you contact us via the CCS email address, our FAQs feedback or contact us forms, we will collect any name or contact details you provide.
This information is collected and disclosed for the purposes of responding to your query or feedback.
Collection of your personal information
We collect personal information about you when you use your account. This includes,
basic identifying details, including your name, work email address and employer, when you create an account;
more detailed optional personal information in your profile, including but not limited to your telephone number and employer address;
information about your activity while using your CCS account is retained in an audit log, including your IP address, user name, log in attempts (successful and unsuccessful), and other technical information relevant to the operation of your account and use of the website;
information about your form usage is retained in an activity log, including but not limited to, the name of the form, the time taken to complete the form and the answers provided.
Personal information collected about others
If you provide information using your CSS account about an individual other than yourself, you are responsible for obtaining the individual’s consent beforehand.
Why we collect personal information
Finance collects personal information to administer and support the CCS website. Information provided when registering allows us to contact you if you experience issues using the website and to confirm you are an employee or other individual, acting in an official capacity for a Government entity.
We also collect information about your user activity and the forms completed when accessing the CCS website for security and fraud purposes and also to assist with troubleshooting and improving user experience.
Consequences if we do not collect personal information
If the personal information outlined above was not collected by Finance, users of the CCS website would not be able to save their work in progress, we would not be able to provide support or meet our security obligations and our ability to improve user experience would be diminished.
Who we disclose your personal information to
Finance does not routinely disclose personal information collected through the CCS website, however we may be required to share the personal information we collect with external contracted service providers, other Australian Government agencies or as otherwise authorised or required by law.
Finance reserves the right to make disclosures to relevant authorities where the use of CCS raises a suspicion that an offence is being, or has been, committed. In the event of an investigation, Finance will provide access to data to any law enforcement agency that may exercise a warrant to inspect CCS records.
How long we hold your information
Information collected through the generation of forms and draft documents is retained within the CCS website for 12 months from date of creation to allow reasonable time for business use and record keeping.
Personal information relating to website usage (logs) are stored in Finance’s record management system for 7 years as required under the Archives Act 1983.
Did you find this content useful?
Your comments (if any)
Page
Submit
Contact
ccsdesk@finance.gov.au
Content Focus
Audience
Government
Topic
Procurement
Updated: 28 August 2020Related Resources
Policies, legislation and guidelines
Commonwealth Contracting Suite (CCS)
Footer
Accessibility
Contact us
Copyright
Disclaimer
Information Publication Scheme
Privacy
© Commonwealth of Australia 2020
Frequently Asked Questions - Advertising
Guidelines on Information and Advertising Campaigns by non-corporate Commonwealth entities
Indigenous Audience Research
Online Management System – UM Central
Recruitment Advertising Policy (RMG 408)
Role of Finance
Types of advertising
White Pages Advertising Guidance
Assurance Reviews and Risk Assessment
Assurance Reviews Process Overview
Becoming a Private Sector Reviewer
Becoming a Public Sector Reviewer
Gateway Reviews Process
ICT Investment Approval Process
ICT Investment Approval Process - Frequently asked questions
ICT Investment Approval Process - Text Descriptions
Implementation Readiness Assessment (IRA)
Lessons Learned - Gateway Reviews
Gateway Reviews Process - Lessons Learned - Second Edition
Questions & Answers For Review Team Members on the Assurance Reviews Process
Questions & Answers: For Senior Responsible Officials on the Assurance Reviews Process
Australian Government Investment Funds
Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Land and Sea Future Fund
Clean Energy Finance Corporation
DisabilityCare Australia Fund
Future Drought Fund
Future Fund
Governance - Investment Funds
Future Fund Board of Guardians
Future Fund Management Agency
International Forum of Sovereign Wealth Funds
Claims Management
Background information about the Cornwell superannuation case
Claim Forms - Comcover
Claims
Education
Building Risk Management Capability
Embedding an active risk culture Part 2: The benefits of an active risk culture
Embedding an active risk culture
Organisational Resilience in a Crisis
Risk Management in a Crisis
Risk appetite and tolerance
Insurance
Comcover - expired policies
Frequently asked questions - insurance
Indemnity and Insurance Clauses in Commonwealth Contracts
Digital Records Investment Alignment Process
Sourcing Strategy Framework (DRTI) – Phase A. Problem Definition
Sourcing Strategy Framework (DRTI) – Phase B. Sourcing
Sourcing Strategy Framework (DRTI) – Phase C. Retrospective
Sourcing Strategy Framework
Federal Budget
Central Budget Management System (CBMS)
CBMS Access
CBMS Data Management – Reference Data Set
CBMS Training
Parliamentary Budget Office
The Budget Process
Financial reporting and accounting policy
Chief Finance Officer (CFO) stewardship forum
Financial Statements Better Practice Guide
6. Actioning and monitoring the plan
7. Development processes and procedures – Financial Statements Better Practice Guide
8. Structuring the financial statements – Financial Statements Better Practice Guide
9. Quality assurance and certifications
Financial reporting for Commonwealth entities
Frequently Asked Questions – Accounting Impacts of COVID-19 and related matters
Guide to classifying payments to other levels of government for specific purposes and Commonwealth own-purpose expenses
Overview of Commonwealth financial reporting
Functional reporting
Description of functions and sub-functions
Government Finance Statistics
Major fiscal
Technical accounting policy and guidance
Governance
Commonwealth Contracting Suite – Privacy Statement
Managing Commonwealth Resources
Annual performance statements for Commonwealth entities (RMG 134)
Annual report for corporate Commonwealth entities (RMG 136)
Annual report for non-corporate Commonwealth entities (RMG 135)
Annual reports for Commonwealth companies (RMG 137)
Australian Government Grants – Briefing, Reporting, Evaluating and Election Commitments (RMG 412)
Clarification of the terms ‘Audit’ and ‘Assurance’ (RMG 210)
Commonwealth companies Executive Remuneration Reporting Guide for Annual Reports (RMG 139)
Commonwealth entities Executive Remuneration Reporting Guide for Annual Reports (RMG 138)
Corporate plans for Commonwealth entities (RMG 132)
Developing good performance information (RMG 131)
General duties of officials (RMG 203)
Implementing the Commonwealth Risk Management Policy (RMG 211)
Learning and support
eLearning and training modules
Managing money & property
Managing Money
Annual Appropriations
Portfolio Budget Statements
Australian Government Charging Framework
Charging Activities
Charging for commercial activities
Charging for regulatory activities (Cost Recovery)
Charging for resource activities
Portfolio Charging Reviews
Portfolio Charging Reviews
The Charging Framework
The Charging Framework
Banking Money
Borrowing
Collecting revenue or money
Entering arrangements and committing relevant money
Indemnities
Investment by Commonwealth Entities
Making a payment of an amount owed to a person at time of death
Managing Debt
Other CRF Money
Receiving money
Spending money
Managing risk & internal accountability
Duties
Duties
Duties of Accountable Authorities
Officials
Risk & Internal Controls
Accountable Authority Instructions (AAIs) - RMG 206
Audit committees
How to set-up and manage an audit committee
Information for audit committee members
Joint Committee of Public Accounts and Audit - Responding to Parliamentary Committee Reports
Prescribing officials
Reporting Non-compliance
Foreign exchange risk management
Notification of significant non-compliance with the finance law (RMG 214)
PGPA Legislation
Planning and reporting
Annual Reporting
Commonwealth Performance Framework
Measuring
Planning
Reporting
Prescribing officials (RMG 212)
Preventing, detecting and dealing with fraud (RMG 201)
The banking of cash by Commonwealth entities (RMG 413)
Structure of the Australian Government Public Sector
Commonwealth Governance Structures Policy (Governance Policy)
Further information on the key requirements of the Governance Policy
Australian Government Organisations Register
Australian Government Organisations Register - Guide to Fields
Australian Government Organisations Register - Types of Bodies
Register of movements list
Spreadsheet of bodies
Summary of Key Statistics
Commonwealth Governance Structures Policy (Governance Policy)
Creating a new government body
PGPA Act Flipchart and List
Reviewing an existing government body
Types of Australian Government Bodies
Ministerial and Parliamentary Services
Procurement
Buying for the Australian Government
Accountability and Transparency
COVID-19 – Procurement Policy Note
Commonwealth Contracting Suite (CCS)
Commonwealth Contracting Suite - Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs)
Commonwealth Procurement Awards for Excellence
2019 Commonwealth Procurement Awards for Excellence – Recipients
Commonwealth Procurement Rules
Accountability and Transparency
Additional Rules
Appendix A: Exemptions
Appendix B: Definitions
Efficient, Effective, Economical and Ethical Procurement
Encouraging Competition
Foreword
Insurance Risk Management
Roles and Responsibilities - AGF, Entity Fleet Managers and sgfleet
Whole of Australian Government Procurement - Buying
Whole-of-Government Procurement Contracts, Arrangements and Initiatives
Property and Construction
Barton Development Site
Capital Works Projects
Commonwealth Land Holdings
Commonwealth Property Disposal Policy
Commonwealth Property Management Framework
About the Commonwealth Property Management Framework
Budgeting and Funding
Land Acquisition and Disposals
Lands Acquisition Act 1989 (LAA)
Leased office accommodation
Australian Government Office Occupancy Report
Property Services Coordinated Procurement
Property Services Coordinated Procurement
Public Works Committee
Setting up a Commonwealth entity
Accommodation
Appointments and staffing
Superannuation
Arrangements for Australian Government employees and statutory office holders
Arrangements Under the Superannuation (Productivity Benefit) Act 1988
Choice of Superannuation Funds for New Australian Government Employees
Commonwealth Superannuation Scheme (CSS)
Governance - Superannuation
Relevant legislation and responsible ministers
Investment fund principles
Public Sector Superannuation Accumulation Plan (PSSAP)
Public Sector Superannuation Scheme (PSS)
Arrangements for Federal Judges, Governors-General and Federal Circuit Court Judges
Governor General
Judge
Judges of the Federal Circuit Court of Australia
Parliamentary Contributory Superannuation Scheme
Parliamentary Superannuation
Overview of the Parliamentary Superannuation Act 2004
Parliamentary Contributory Superannuation Act 1948 - Parliamentary Contributory Superannuation Scheme (PCSS)
Parliamentary Salaries
Parliamentary Contributory Superannuation Act 1948 - Parliamentary Contributory Superannuation Scheme (PCSS)
Superannuation costs and reports
Charges for Actuarial Accounts
Employer Responsibilities & Costs
Judges of the Federal Circuit Court of Australia Long Term Cost Reports
Judges' Pensions Scheme - Long Term Cost Reports
PCSS Long Term Cost Reports
PSS and CSS Long Term Cost Reports
Superannuation Costs for Agencies
The Shared Services Transformation Initiative
GovERP
Shared Services Delivery
The Shared Services Journey
2018 Advices
Whole of Government Information and Communications Technology Services
Data Carriage Service
GovLink
Intra-government Communications Network (ICON)
Ministerial Communications Network (MCN)
National Telepresence System (NTS)
Parliamentary Document Management System (PDMS)
Parliamentary Television (ParlTV)
Business
Find a grant (GrantConnect)
Government Business Enterprises
ASC
Australia Post
Australian Naval Infrastructure Pty Ltd
Australian Rail Track Corporation (ARTC)
Defence Housing Australia (DHA)
Medibank sale
Frequently Asked Questions - Medibank Sale
Moorebank Intermodal Company Limited
NBN Co Limited (nbn)
Past sales
Snowy Hydro Limited
The role of directors in Commonwealth GBE's Guidelines
Director Rules and Duties
Financial Management
Governance Regulation
Overview
Planning and Reporting
WSA Co Limited
Procurement
Complaints Handling Charter Complaints
Whole of Australian Government Procurement - Selling
Individuals
Act of grace payments, waiver of debts to the Commonwealth, Compensation for Detriment caused by Defective Administration (CDDA)
Act of grace payments
Application process
Information for Commonwealth entities about acts of grace and waivers of debt
Scheme for Compensation for Detriment caused by Defective Administration (CDDA Scheme)
Waiver of debt
Find a grant (GrantConnect)
Publications
All Publication Categories
Charter of Budget Honesty - Policy Costing Guidelines
Commonwealth Budget
Corporate Plan 2020-21
Pre-election Economic and Fiscal Outlook
Resource Management Guides
AASB Leases – Implementation Guide (RMG 110)
Accounting for concessional loans (RMG 115)
Accounting for internally developed software (RMG 109)
Accounting for machinery of government changes (RMG 118)
Accounting for non-current assets held for sale (RMG 111)
Accounting for subsequent expenditure on property, plant and equipment (RMG 113)
Audit committees (RMG 202)
Charging Activities (RMG 304)
Commitment of Relevant Money (RMG 400)
Commonwealth Entities Financial Statements Guide (RMG 125)
Commonwealth Grants and Procurement Connected Policies (RMG 415)
Commonwealth Investments (RMG 308)
Corporate plan for Commonwealth companies (RMG 133)
Deeming or designating transfers of assets and liabilities as 'contributions by owners' (equity) (RMG 123)
Disclosure of maturity information in financial statements (RMG 122)
Domestic Travel Policy (RMG 404)
Government Business Enterprises (GBEs) (RMG 126)
Grants, Procurements and other financial arrangements (RMG 411)
Guidance on the Assurance Reviews Process (RMG 106)
Guide to Appropriations (RMG 100)
Handling complaints under the Government Procurement (Judicial Review) Act 2018 (RMG 422)
Identification of general insurance contracts for accounting purposes (RMG 112)
Indemnities (RMG 414)
Investment by Commonwealth entities (RMG 301)
Mandatory use of the Commonwealth Contracting Suite for procurement under $200,000 (RMG 420)
Meeting the Senate Order for Entity Contracts (RMG 403)
Official International Travel – Use of the best fare of the day (RMG 405)
Other CRF money (RMG 303)
Payment pending probate - (RMG 402)
Payment terms for Australian Government Travel Arrangements – card services (RMG 418)
Procurement Publishing and Reporting Obligations (RMG 423)
Publishing and reporting Grants and GrantConnect (RMG 421)
Reporting requirements following machinery of government changes (RMG 119)
Requests for discretionary financial assistance under the
Public Governance, Performance and Accountability Act 2013 (RMG 401)
Restrictions on advertising for open
Approaches to Market (ATMs) (RMG 407)
Retainable receipts (RMG 307)
Risk Potential Assessment Tool General Guidance (RMG 107)
Scheme for Compensation for Detriment caused by Defective Administration (RMG 409)
Supplier Pay On-Time or Pay Interest Policy (RMG 417)
Pay On-Time Policy (RMG 417) - Additional information
The Charging Framework (RMG 302)
https://www.finance.gov.au/sites/default/files/2020-09/RMG%20114%20-%20Accounting%20for%20decommissioning%2C%20restoration%20and%20similar%20provisions%20to%20make%20good.docx
Annual Report 2016-17
Annual Report 2017-18
Annual Report 2018-19
Corporate Plan 2017-18
Corporate Plan 2018-19
Corporate Plan 2019-20
About us
Accessibility
Finance locations - State offices - Ministerial and Parliamentary Services
Copyright
Disclaimer
Freedom of Information
Disclosure log
Information Publication Scheme (IPS)
Information Publication Scheme – Information Publication Plan
